http://bastra.com/private-policy

WE CARE ABOUT YOUR PRIVACY
BASTRA GmbH&Co.KG  (“BASTRA”), is committed to respect your privacy and to comply with applicable data protection and privacy laws. This privacy policy (“Policy”) describes how we collect and use personal data where BASTRA is the data controller or where we refer to the applicability of this Policy. “Personal data” means information relating to you or another identifiable individual.
We will give you additional
privacy information that is specific to a product or service in Supplements to
this Policy and other notices you may see while using our products or services.
If there is a difference between such notices and this Policy, the notices
should be considered first.
Software on your device may
access your information. Our products or services may contain links to, or may
be embedded within, other companies’ websites and services that have privacy
policies of their own. Where our products or services are embedded to products
and services of our customers, we require our customers to provide necessary
transparency to you. This might include linking to this Policy and the relevant
Supplements, or providing the transparency in integrated and embedded notices
which identify us as the service provider or controller.
If you do not agree
with this Policy, do not use our products and services or provide BASTRA with
your personal data.
What information do we collect?
We collect your personal
data and other information when you make a purchase, use or register into our
products and services (including navigation.com stores, which are branded by
Original Equipment Manufacturers (“OEMs”) and operated by us), take part in
campaigns or research or otherwise interact with us. This includes following
categories:
Product and service
activations
BASTRA products and
services may require electronic activation, where your device and application
type, as well as unique device, application, network and subscription
identifiers are sent to BASTRA.
Use of products and
services
When you access our
services online, our web servers automatically create records of your visit.
These records typically include IP-address, access times, the sites linked
from, pages visited, the links and features used, the content viewed or
requested, browser or application type, language and other such information.
See also our Cookie policy.
Our applications may
contact our servers periodically, for example to check for updates or to send
us information relating to service usage. Additionally, we may invite you to
join voluntary product and service improvement or research programs where
detailed information is collected. See Supplements to this Policy for more
details.
Information you provide us with
When you create an account,
make a purchase, request services, participate in research or campaigns or
otherwise interact with us, we may ask for information such as your name, email
address, phone number, street address, user names and passwords, feedback,
information relating to your devices, age, gender, and language, bank account
number, credit card details and other such financial information.
We also maintain records of your consents, preferences and settings relating
to, for example, location data, marketing and sharing of personal data.
Your transactions
with us
We maintain records of your
purchases, downloads, the content you have provided us with, your requests,
agreements between you and BASTRA, the products and services provided to you,
payment and delivery details, your contacts and communications and other
interactions with us. We may, in accordance with applicable law, record your
communication with our customer care or with other such contact points.
Positioning and
Location data
Location-based services
establish location through the use of satellite, mobile, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth Low
Energy (“BLE”) or other network based positioning methods. These technologies
may involve exchanging your location data and unique device and mobile, Wi-Fi,
Bluetooth, or other network related identifiers with BASTRA. Our products may
operate on multiple device platforms, applications and services which may also
collect your location data. We do not use this information to identify you
personally without your consent.
When you use our location
based services and features, for example location based search, navigation and
routing, or request for map data, your location data is sent to BASTRA to serve
you with the right content, which may also include location based advertising.
Information
provided by partners
We obtain information from
industry partners and a variety of other sources, including publicly available
sources such as business registries. We require these sources to comply with
applicable laws with regard to collecting and transferring this data to us,
including ensuring that there is a legal basis for the transfer or anonymizing
the data in accordance with applicable laws prior to disclosure of the data to
us.
Why do we process Personal Data?
BASTRA may process your
personal data for the following purposes. One or more purposes may apply
simultaneously.
Providing products
and services
We may use your personal
data to provide you with our products and services, to process your requests or
as otherwise may be necessary to perform the contract between you and BASTRA,
to ensure the functionality and security of our products and services, to
identify you as well as to prevent and investigate fraud and other misuses.
Accounts
Some services may require
an account to help you manage your content and preferences. Depending on the
service, an account creation may be either required or voluntary. Account
creation requires you to provide us with basic contact details about yourself,
such as name, email address, country of residence and date of birth. You may
also be able to voluntarily provide more information about yourself while
creating a profile, such as a photo or avatar of your choice.
Developing and
managing products and services
We may use your personal
data to develop and manage our products, services, customer care, sales and
marketing. We may combine personal data collected in connection with your use
of a particular BASTRA product and/or service with other personal data we may
have about you, unless such personal data was collected for a purpose, where
the original purpose is incompatible with this purpose.
Communicating with
you
We may use your personal
data to communicate with you, for example to inform you that our services have
changed or to send you critical alerts and other such notices relating to our
products and/or services and to contact you for customer care related purposes.
Marketing,
advertising and making recommendations
We may contact you to
inform you of new products, services or promotions we may offer and to conduct
market research when we have your consent or it is otherwise allowed. We may
use your personal data to personalize our offering and to provide you with more
relevant services, for example, to make recommendations and to display customized
content and advertising in our services. This may include displaying BASTRA and
third party content.
What is our legal
basis for processing your Personal Data?
Our legal basis for
processing your personal data is dependent on the purpose for processing and
may vary as described in the Supplement applicable to the product or service
you are using. In general, we process your personal data under the following
legal bases:
Performance of a
contract with you
We process your personal
data to perform our obligations under the Service Terms applicable to the
product or service you are using, provided by us or our customers.
Your consent
We process your personal
data if you have consented to the processing activity. You may revoke your
consent at any time. Doing so will bar us from further processing of your
personal data based on your consent, but will not impact the lawfulness of
processing based on your consent before it was withdrawn. Some of the features
of our products and services might be only available based on consent.
Legal obligations
We process your personal
data as needed to comply with laws and regulations.
Legitimate
interests
We process your personal
data to further our legitimate interests, such as in connection with managing,
developing, testing, securing, and in limited circumstances marketing,
advertising, and making recommendations regarding our products and services.
Any such processing is conducted subject to appropriate measures to protect
your fundamental rights and freedoms related to your personal data, and in any
event will be subject to the restrictions provided in this Policy. Further
information or specification of our legitimate interests may be provided in
relevant Supplements applicable to the product or service.
How long do
we retain Personal Data?
We endeavor to only collect
personal data that are necessary for the purposes for which they are collected,
and to retain such data for no longer than is necessary for such purposes. The
length of time personal data is retained, and criteria for determining that
time, are dependent on the nature of the personal data and the purpose for
which it was provided. For example, for your personal data related to managing
your account (such as name, email address, and account content and preferences)
are maintained for as long as they are retained by you within your account.
Other data, such as records of your activity within the application, are
typically maintained only for a short period before being anonymized or
pseudonymized. Additional information may be provided in the Supplement
applicable to the product or service you are using.
Do we share Personal Data?
We do not sell, lease, rent
or otherwise disclose your personal data to third parties unless otherwise
stated below.
Your consent and
social sharing services
We may share your personal
data if we have your consent to do so. Some services may allow you to share
your personal data with other users of the service or with other services and
their users. Please consider carefully before disclosing any personal data or
other information that might be accessible to other users.
BASTRA companies
and authorized third parties
We may share your personal
data with other BASTRA companies or authorized third parties who process personal
data for BASTRA for the purposes described in this Policy. This may include for
example billing through your network service provider or otherwise, delivery of
your purchases, providing services including customer service, managing and
analyzing consumer data, credit checks, conducting research and managing
marketing and other such campaigns. When you purchase a BASTRA product from us
with a network service provider plan, we may need to exchange information with
your network service provider to provide you with such service.
We may conduct joint
marketing and other communications with our partners, for example your mobile
operator. To avoid duplicate or unnecessary communications and to tailor the
message to you we may need to match information that BASTRA has collected with
information that the partner has collected where this is permitted by law.
These authorized third
parties are not permitted to use your personal data for any other purposes. We
bind them contractually, require them to act consistently with this Policy and
to use appropriate security measures to protect your personal data.
International
transfers of personal data
Our products and services
may be provided using resources and servers located in various countries around
the world. Therefore your personal data may be transferred across international
borders outside the country where you use our services, including to countries
outside the European Economic Area (EEA) that do not have laws providing
specific protection for personal data or that have different legal rules on
data protection, for example, the United States of America. In such cases we
ensure that there is a legal basis for such a transfer and that adequate
protection for your personal data is provided as required by applicable law, for
example, by using standard contractual clauses approved by the European
Commission or relevant authorities (where necessary) and by requiring the use
of other appropriate technical and organizational information security
measures.
Mandatory disclosures
We may be obligated by
mandatory law to disclose your personal data to certain authorities or other
third parties, for example, to law enforcement agencies in the countries where
we or third parties acting on our behalf operate. We may also disclose and
otherwise process your personal data in accordance with applicable law to
defend BASTRA’s legitimate interests, for example, in legal proceedings or in
connection with governmental requests and filings.
Mergers and
Acquisitions
If we decide to sell, buy,
merge or otherwise reorganize our businesses in certain countries, this may
involve us disclosing personal data to prospective or actual purchasers and
their advisers, or receiving personal data from sellers and their advisers.
How do we address Data Quality?
We take reasonable steps to
keep the personal data we possess accurate and to delete incorrect or
unnecessary personal data.
We encourage you to access
your personal data through your account from time to time to ensure that it is
up to date.
What steps are taken to safeguard Personal Data?
Privacy and security are
key considerations in the creation and delivery of our products and services.
We have assigned specific responsibilities to address privacy and security
related matters. We enforce our internal policies and guidelines through an
appropriate selection of activities, including proactive and reactive risk
management, security and privacy engineering, training and assessments. We take
appropriate steps to address online security, physical security, risk of data
loss and other such risks taking into consideration the risk represented by the
processing and the nature of the data being protected. Also, we limit access to
our data bases containing personal data to authorized persons having a
justified need to access such information.
How do we use Cookies and Web Beacons?
BASTRA uses cookies, web
beacons and other similar technologies to operate and improve our websites and
offerings. We also use cookies for personalization and to display ads. Some BASTRA
websites use third party advertising technologies, such as DoubleClick, to
serve ads.
Our domains may include
third party elements that set cookies on behalf of a third party, for example
relating to third party social network. Please visit our Cookie policy to find out more about how BASTRA uses cookies
and how you can disable cookies by browser settings or otherwise.
What are your rights?
You have a right to know
what personal data we hold about you, and to access it. You have a right to
have incomplete, incorrect, unnecessary or outdated personal data updated. You
have the right to request that your personal data be erased, and to obtain a
copy of your data in a machine-readable format. You have the right to object to
or restrict processing in certain circumstances, such as where you believe the
data is inaccurate or the processing activity is unlawful. You have a right to unsubscribe
from direct marketing messages and to request that we stop processing your
personal data for direct marketing purposes or on other compelling legal
grounds. However, if you opt-out from marketing and other communications from BASTRA,
critical alerts may still be sent to you. If you are located in a European
Union member state or within the European Economic Area, you have the right to
lodge a complaint about our data collection and processing activities with the
supervisory authority concerned.
You may exercise your
rights by contacting us or by managing your account and choices through
available profile management tools on your device and our services. In some
cases, especially if you wish us to delete or stop processing your personal
data, this may also mean that we may not be able to continue to provide the
services to you. Applicable data protection law may provide certain
restrictions on the extent to which these rights may be exercised. If a
restriction applies, we will respond to your request with an explanation of
what action will be taken, to the extent required under applicable data
protection law.
Who is the controller of your Personal Data?
BASTRA GmbH&Co.KG, 45309
Essen, Germany is the controller of your personal data.
In addition, the BASTRA
affiliate providing the product or service may be a controller of your personal
data. You may find the identity of the controller and its contact details by
reviewing the terms and conditions of such a product or service or by using
contact information provided in the applicable BASTRA websites.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
BASTRA may from time to time change this Policy or change, modify or withdraw access to this site at any time with or without notice. However, if this Policy is changed in a material, adverse way, BASTRA will post a notice advising of such change at the beginning of this Policy and on this site’s home page for 30 days. We recommend that you re-visit this Policy from time to time to learn of any such changes to this Policy.
